Welcome! In this second part
of decision making without probabilities,
we will be discussing the
Equally-Likely approach and we'll also be discussing
the Realism approach. We will be using
this Payoff table and assume
payoffs are profits. The equally likely
or Laplace approach. Using this approach
we choose the alternative
with the best average payoff. To find the
average payoff
we add the payoffs in a decision alternative and divide the total by the number of payoffs
With bonds,
the average  payoff is 30. The average
is 29 for stocks, and the average
is 31 for Mutual Funds. The best of these
is 31. Therefore the equally likely
decision
is to invest in Mutual Funds.
The Realism or Hurwicz
approach.
This approach find a compromise between the best
and worst payoffs. Using this approach we choose the alternative
with the best weighted average payoff based
on the coefficient of realism α. The coefficient
of realism α is a value between
0 & 1
determined by the decision maker. For each decision alternative,
the approach here is to multiply the best payoff by α
multiplied the worst payoff
by 1 minus α, and then add the two
results.
Note that when of α close to 1
decision-maker is optimistic, and when α is close 0
the decision maker is pessimistic. In
this example
we choose α equals 0.3.
And thus, 1 minus α
is 0.7. This indicates that the decision-maker is leaning towards
pessimism. Let us now calculate the
weighted
average for each decision. For Bonds
the best payoff is 45 and the
worst is 5.
So we calculate 0.3 times 45
plus 0.7 times 5
and the result is 17. For Stocks
the best payoff is 70 and the worst
is negative 13
The weighted average
is .3 times 70 plus .7 times
-13 which gives 11.9
For Mutual Funds, the best payoff is 53
and the worst is -5. The weighted average
.3 times 53 plus .7 seven times -5
which equals 12.4. The best
of these is 17. Therefore the realism
approach
decision is to invest in bonds.
In this video I have shown how to
make decisions
using the equally likely and realism
approaches.
Thanks for watching!